I hope to see you again.
Best regards.
My name is Shinobu Watanabe,
I am in an indie trio band called Asfaragas,
I am a guitarist and vocalist,
I'm a guitarist and vocalist, and I'm also a songwriter,
I also write songs for them,
I've been making some music for "Bartender Girl Daisai" as well.
I am looking forward to working with you.
What I wanted to ask you the most, or rather, what I was curious about in the first place, was,
I was wondering if you would make a third album with Ms. Ooi on it, and then make a fourth album with her on it,
I thought it was a very unusual case to make an album with Mr. Oi in it.
I think it is a very rare case to include Mr. Oi in an album.
Normally, people would complain about it. I have the impression that the trademark was included.
However, the version is different. It is a new member's version.
But I am wondering why they decided to make another version.
I am curious too.
Really?
But it's not just me. The Angel Girls team.
It's everyone's consensus that this phenomenon of Ms. Ooi's..,
I want to expand on this.
I really didn't want it to end with just one song by Ms. Oi,
So, with Ms. Oi as the axis of the project, I thought, why not an album?
That's how it all started.
I would like to know how you changed the direction of the album so drastically that you ended up making something like that.
Me?
Yes, you did.
Why did Mr. Shinobu change the direction of his music from the rock style that he had been doing until then?
I was wondering why Mr. Shinobu had been playing rock-oriented songs until then, and why he decided to switch to Mr. Oi's hammering style.
When I originally wrote that song, I mentioned it to Mr. Sugimoto,
I was like, "Let it be buried in the album a little bit, because it's totally different from the nuance of what you've done before,
I thought it was kind of cool for me,
I thought it was cool, but it was so different from my image of him that I felt sorry for him,
I have always had a bit of a strange personality,
Well, I'm a bit strange.
I am really strange.
So, to put it another way,
I am so strange that only Mr. Sugimoto would ask me to do various things.
I don't know how to put it.
It's a bit strange.
When Mr. Sugimoto first asked me to write a song, I was probably a little bit strange,
I guess it's more like,
What was the first song of your major label debut?
Oshoi.
Oshoi, I forgot I wrote it.
It was like "Oshoi," but refreshed again,
I guess you were expecting some nuance of "Oshoi," like, "Let's refresh ourselves and go again," or something like that?
Yes, I think so. Oshoi was originally the starting song of the group,
Oshoi is an evolved version of it.
It is an evolution of the original oshoi, which was the starting song of the group, and then it became oisa, oisa, oisa.
Just like the actual flow of the culture of the mountain umbrella,
I have wanted to write a song called "Oisa" for a long time,
I thought that Shinobu-san would be the best person to ask,
I thought it would be great if the song could coincide with the story of the Batention's going one step further,
That's what I had in mind.
At that time, did you have any communication with them, asking them to please use a typed version of the song?
At that time, we didn't have any restrictions.
I was not bound to that kind of thing in the first place.
I am sorry about that.
I don't tie myself to kicks very much.
I'm sorry.
When I debuted, I was tied up pretty tightly,
But at that time, I had a ska-punk taste, and there was a flash in the pan,
But at that time, I had a ska-punk taste, and I responded to that,
This time, however, I was asked to be a little more open-minded,
In other words, I have more freedom,
I also had a little bit of Shinobu's gacha in me,
Yes, Shinobu gacha.
I just say, "I got this one, depending on my mood at the time," and that may be all.
It was really just a coincidence,
No, it was really just a coincidence.
It was just my mood at the time?
Yes, it was. It was just my mood,
It only became more Japanese after the song was completed,
I didn't write it with a Japanese feeling.
I tend to add things after the fact, and it's a lot of "rock-paper-scissors-scissors" kind of thing.
So, if anything,
For example, Mr. Kanno was very excited to hear my ideas,
But I want to make an aggressive song,
He would say, "That's fine,They would say something like, "That's fine,
But it was more like, what should I do?
I closed my eyes and went ah-ha, and they all collapsed.
They all fell down.
We were all falling down,
In short, the deadline soon exceeds the scripture,
The deadline was the scripture.
So, when we were pushed into a corner and did something like, "Aaah!
And when I did that, they all fell down,
And the people around me would applaud, so I would stand up for myself.
I've been doing this for years.
But when I was pushed into a corner,
It was really interesting that I made it from a track instead of just using the guitar, which I'm good at,
I don't really care about the way I write songs.
I didn't pay much attention to how the songs were written,
I didn't care too much about how the song was written, just the guitar or piano, for example,
There is an abundance of good equipment,
But in the end, the songs come from my own humming, which is really the root.
It's all about humming and imagination,
It's just something vague, something that I think of far and away.
I think it's just something vague and vague,
So I started with a bass track.
So I started out with a bass track, and just played "do-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo,
And then I tried singing with it,
And then I would add a little bit at a time to the original bass line.
I had the original bass line, and I kept looping it while singing,
So it became loop music?
Maybe, as a result.
The loose, loose feel I mentioned earlier is also a part of the music,
I was also aiming for that,
Shinobu-san is also a composer,
Shinobu-san is a composer as well as a producer.
Shinobu-san is also a composer, and he is a great producer,
I had the impression that he has a very precise grasp of what these children would be interested in doing next,
I have known Hitomu-san since we started working together on Kaera-chan,
I've known Hitomu since we started working together on the Kaera-chan project,
I had the impression that Hitomu had an eye for producing,
That's why I have asked her to produce several songs for me.
It is no surprise that the melodies and lyrics are always wonderful,
But there is always something that these kids are doing right now.
This is something that staff members who deal with virtual shows on a daily basis can't come up with,
They keep coming back to us from here.
But it is very rare to find such a person.
It's exciting, and I look forward to it every time,
It's also a bit of a rush.
But on the other hand, I am really happy if you let me be free to do what I want.
For example, they often ask me to write a song like this one I wrote in the past,
Or, I am asked to write a song like this one that I have written in the past, or a song by an unknown artist,
I don't mean to say that it makes me wince, but it does.
Well, that is true.
It's no fun to write the same song.
And you can't make it.
Even if you were asked to write a song like that, I don't think any writer could do it,
I don't think any writer would be able to do it.
In fact, I think they would think it was terrible in their hearts.
Surprisingly, there are quite a few of them,
It is a mixture of various things that make up the song,
If the artist changes the singer, the music will change completely.
The way you hear it will also change as the time period changes,
So it is quite difficult to redo the music, if that is the right way to put it,
And if the music is said to be like a song by someone I don't know at all, I'm not sure if I should say, "Oh, that's not me,
And if it sounds like a song by someone I don't know at all, I wonder if it's okay to say, "Oh, that's not me,
In that sense, Sumima-san allowed me to do what I wanted,
In that sense, Sumima-san lets me do what I want, and I get a lot of responses saying, "That sounds pretty interesting,
So I thought, "Well, I'll do it too.
And then they all collapsed.
And when they fell down, the people around them became like this, and they were proud.
I really do have this tendency.
But I completely ignore my past tendencies.
It's my personality, isn't it?
I want to enjoy myself.
I want to be excited.
I want to be aggressive, and as I mentioned before in a previous interview, I also like to watch what's on Youtube,
There are many idols out there,
I feel like the seventh member, and it's frustrating.
I don't know,
I think there are rules, theories, and idol mannerisms,
It is very difficult to fight in such a situation,
In other words, it becomes a battle of skills,
In other words, it becomes a battle of skills, so why don't you stay in a different place?Then you should be in a different place now,
I won't tell you what Mr. Sugiyama said before,
I don't want to tell you what Mr. Sugiyama said before, but it is better to go to a place where you cannot be compared,
I personally feel the same way,
I personally, too, would like to see the era of General Mateen become such a place,
I was also motivated by this desire.
On the contrary,
On the other hand, the loop is so strong that you can listen to it for a long time and wonder how the song was closed.
I thought that was amazing.
It's really just a coincidence.
It really was just a coincidence.
I don't think I was conscious of that.
I set up the loop.
I was just thinking, "I'm going to sing a flower song like this.
Maybe that's how I was doing it.
So when you talk about MISOGI THE MUSIC
I might not have intended it that way.
It's just the impression I got.
When that came in the second half of the album
We've done a lot of aggressive songs.
but it sounds like we're singing idol songs.
I thought that was really interesting.
Did you have the theme of "MISOGI" in mind at the beginning?
Yes, it was.
What do you mean by "festival"?
I was thinking of another theme for the bar that doesn't directly say festival.
I was thinking of something that I, as a member of Batten, feel.
It's a little bit sacred.
or a feeling of purity...
I'm trying to think of a word to express that.
I was thinking of a word to express that feeling.
MISOGI is a pretty hard word.
MISOGI is a rather hard word, but it has an interesting sound.
We also wondered if Shinobu-san could come up with something for us.
We also thought that Mr. Shinobu would make something up, so we just threw it out there.
I was told "MISOGI" and I thought, "Why this?
Why is this?
Why is it that my impression of MISOGI is that people who have done bad things are liquidated by MISOGI?
People who have done bad things are purified by MISOGI.
That's why these girls...
I don't know, but...
I don't know.
It gives the impression that they did something bad.
Like a slaughterhouse.
I asked Ai Keyama, one of the members, about it.
I've never robbed a bike.
Like, "No, you haven't.
I wouldn't write something like that.
Check it out.
I don't know, but it's just for reference.
As a reference.
You've never done that before, have you?
Of course not. That's what they said.
Why would MISO let those kids do that?
That's where it starts.
Why should they have MISO?
After all...
They can have MISO at the live performance.
right?
That's right.
The live performance is the act of MISOGI.
It's an act of MISOGI.
It's not just about the girls.
It's not just the girls.
I mean, not only the girls, but also the fans
Let's wash it away.
Even those who haven't done anything wrong.
It's okay.
It's just daily stress.
Stress.
They're training.
They practice dancing.
Singing, too.
They train day in and day out.
They train hard.
And then you show the results of your training.
And then, just like that...
Because it's at a live performance that you can let it all out.
In that sense
MISOGI is a live performance.MISOGI is a live performance.
First of all
From there, I thought about the lyrics.
I thought about the lyrics.
I really thought...
I guess it's all about messing around after all.
That's why I was a little twisted when I wrote Greetings
When I wrote MISOGI, I was more straightforward.
My feelings were a little more punk-ish.
Idols...
That's exactly how the lyrics are performed live.
Dancing like this
That's what makes people happy.
That's what it's all about.
I don't know what to say first.
It's a lot of things, but it's
I think it's the root of it all.
It's really a simple message, isn't it?
It's a simple message, isn't it?
I think to myself.
There was a theme of salvation.
You were the only one who spoke differently.
But in the end, it all came together.
It came together a little bit.
Yes, it did.
When I made it punk-ish...
You said, "Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
They say, "Oh, this is great.
Yeah, right.
But I didn't mean to summarize.
Salvation is salvation
I'm going to save you.
The double-meaning is
I've always been trying to figure out how to digest that.
That's the underlying theme.
Another underlying theme
I've been trying to figure out how to digest it.
I was thinking that I didn't have to digest it
But still...
I was able to digest it a little bit at Misogi.
This is a bad idea, isn't it?
That's right.
And yes, Nanbu-san
About Shinobu-san's lyrics
Yes, yes, yes, yes
No, really
This feeling...
What can I say?
Despite the brightness
The lyrics are so delicate.
Yes, it is.
I was able to express the members'
feelings and many other things
I'm sure you'll be able to understand
I don't know how to say it.
I think it's wonderful that you captured the fog of the mind of the members
I think it's brilliant.
I don't know, though.
I guess you can guess my hobbies...
I'm sure you know what I mean.
I'm trying to understand how Eriro feels.
It's my hobby to guess.
I wonder if he's thinking like this.
That's my hobby.
People are all kinds of things.
People have different feelings.
That's why I think...
Just in XX.
I've made so far.
I think it's the same with Osh.
What else have you made?
Ki Meissen
So I think the lyrics of that one
I think that's how people feel at this time of the year.
In the case of Osh, it's more like...
I don't know.
I want to support them too.I want to support them as well.
It's like I want to support them, too.
And you, Meissen...
I don't know...
It's not about going one step further.
But this time, I really think that each of us
I don't know...
I don't know how to say it.
I was thinking about whether now is the right time to show our hidden strength.
I was also thinking about whether it was the right time to show our hidden strength, and I was thinking a lot about that, and that's how we were doing it.
I was also thinking about the Corona disaster, and that kind of seething feeling is something I also share.
It's easy to link those feelings to your own, and I felt the same way during that period.
I think it's partly because of that... and partly because of my personality.
I mean, I'm like, "He's like this," or "He's shy," or "He's a show-off.
She's selfish or she's greedy.
Or maybe I'm selfish... or greedy.
So you want to have all of them.
I've got everything, like I've got both a negative and positive side.
I'm also very humble.
I'm like a chair bakan. I have it all.
I don't know what's going to happen to it.
I'm shaking a little bit. I'm shaking.
I don't know what's going to come out.
It's a mess of books, inside me. That's why it's hard to handle.
I think that's why it's hard for me to handle.
I think that's why it's hard for me to handle it, but maybe that's why I go into that kind of mode when I'm a singer.
I have their trust.
I also have their trust and my adolescent feelings.
I think there might be a mixture of things.
You've been on stage before.
I wonder what kind of interactions we'll have next time we're on stage.
I'm sure there will be good feedback.
I'm sure there will be.
It's really dangerous if you don't watch your language.
I say things like that, but that's what I'm afraid of.
It's scary.
I'm afraid I'm going to show a really bad one on the mc.
So you're worried about that?
That's right, that's why I have my own band.
Last time I went to a Batten concert.
I told him I'd go to his band's show, too.
I'm definitely not coming.
It's not good for my education.
I guess I'm like this.
But I can change my mode.
I can change my personality.
It's too funny.
It's called Fancy Mode.
Fancy mode.
You can do it in fancy mode.
I love it. It's got so many different modes.
Then, Mr. Shinnumu, let me play the lottery again.
Yes, let's do it!
Let's do two gachas!
So we've heard a lot of stories. But this is Shinumu Watanabe.
Thank you very much.
Anida Anida Anida Anida